<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Théo RICHER | Curriculum vitæ</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/</link><description>Recent content on Théo RICHER | Curriculum vitæ</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>{currentYear} - Théo RICHER | &lt;a href="https://theoricher.pro/fr/">French Version&lt;/a> - &lt;a href="https://theoricher.pro/en/legal-notices/">Legal Notices&lt;/a> - &lt;a href="https://theoricher.pro/en/privacy-policy/">Privacy Policy&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theoricher.pro/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Systems, Networks and Security Engineer - ValSoftware</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/systems-networks-engineer-valsoftware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/systems-networks-engineer-valsoftware/</guid><description>Systems, networks and security engineer in the technical department in the infrastructure service. Responsible for MCO and activity planning, supplier and service provider relations, partner prospecting. Management of several projects: migration of VMWare cluster between datacenters using the Zerto solution. Implementation of an asset management policy and solution using tools such as WAPT and GLPI.
Main tasks :
Responsible for ensuring the consistency and sustainability of the information system (servers, databases, networks, backups); Contribute to the evolution of the company&amp;rsquo;s tools, methods and internal processes; Ensuring compliance of IT infrastructures according to ANSSI best practices; Assistance to customers (N3 support); Example projects :</description></item><item><title>Project Manager: Systems, Networks and Security - ValSoftware</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/project-manager-valsoftware/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/project-manager-valsoftware/</guid><description>Apprentice in the technical department in the infrastructure service, in charge of the MCO of the internal and customers information system. Project manager on different missions: backups, monitoring, budgets, audit.
Main tasks :
Upgrading and maintaining servers in operational condition; Contribute to the evolution of tools and processes; Management of the department ; Project management and initiative taking; Example projects :
Implementation of a monitoring and visualisation solution; Management of an audit on the global overhaul of the backup system; Management of the workstation replacement campaign; Examples of activities :</description></item><item><title>Project Manager: Systems, Networks and Security - IPI Toulouse (Level BAC+5)</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/education/cdpi-ipi-toulouse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/education/cdpi-ipi-toulouse/</guid><description> Be able to integrate the client&amp;rsquo;s request and formalise it in a project proposal; Be able to analyse the impact of the solutions to be implemented and project them into the future; Be able to estimate and optimise the proposed solution, evaluate the interoperability of technical solutions; Be able to communicate in writing in both French and English; Ability to communicate in writing in both French and English; Ability to listen effectively, to be available, to be reactive and to provide effective coaching; Ability to negotiate in a win/win context, to reconcile requirements and constraints; Be able to conduct interviews, mobilise and lead teams towards performance; Be able to control the level of deviation between the planned and the realised, evaluate the impact of exceeding the steering and control indicators;</description></item><item><title>System, Network and Database Administrator - ValSoftware</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/system-network-administrator-valsoftware/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/system-network-administrator-valsoftware/</guid><description>Apprentice in the technical department in the infrastructure service, in charge of the MCO of the internal and customer information system.
Main tasks :
Ensure the consistency and sustainability of the information system (servers, databases, networks, backups, workstations); Assistance to customers: N2 &amp;amp; N3 support; Update operating process; Example projects :
Implementation of a backup solution with centralized management for all Microsoft Windows servers; Implementation and management of a WDS &amp;amp; MDT deployment server; Examples of activities :</description></item><item><title>Administrator: Systems, Networks and Databases - IPI Toulouse (Level BAC+3)</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/education/asrbd-ipi-toulouse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/education/asrbd-ipi-toulouse/</guid><description>Implement a backup plan in case of network failure; Set up the virtualisation of network and hardware equipment, deploy mobile equipment solutions (Wifi, PDA, laptops, tablets, etc.), install, configure and troubleshoot server-side databases (access, sharing, etc.); Query a database in SQL mode; Establish an inventory of the park based on ITIL practices; Deploying active protection elements: proxy, firewalls, anti-virus, etc; Mitigate I.S. attacks (IP Spoofing, DNS failure, architecture failure, vulnerability exploitation, virus, denial of service, etc.</description></item><item><title>Systems, Networks and Security Technician at Spie for Airbus - SPIE ICS</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/systems-networks-security-technician-spie-airbus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/systems-networks-security-technician-spie-airbus/</guid><description>Apprentice systems and networks technician at Spie ICS for Airbus Commercial Aircraft. My role consisted of working directly with users on the customer site to provide them with technical assistance.
Main tasks :
Technical assistance (hardware and software) to users (L2); Remote or on-site intervention; Respect of intervention deadlines (SLA); Example projects :
Creation of an ISO (Live-CD) in accordance with the needs of the company and the technical constraints of the security of the Airbus information system, allowing most of the troubleshooting actions to be carried out on the user stations; Realization of a tool (based on batch) allowing to automate and accelerate some redundant administration actions; Examples of activities :</description></item><item><title>Advanced Technician in Digital Technologies - IPI Toulouse (Level BAC+2)</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/education/tstn-ipi-toulouse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/education/tstn-ipi-toulouse/</guid><description>Deploying hardware, systems and software:
Interconnect client and mobile devices to the corporate network; Install and configure network hardware and services; Integrate servers into the company&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure; Securing and maintaining heterogeneous IT equipment:
Deploy, implement security solutions; Diagnose incidents and problems and resolve them in strict accordance with logical and methodological processes; Administering heterogeneous servers and a multi-site network:
Implement virtualisation of network and hardware equipment; Install, configure and troubleshoot servers (access, shares, storage, blade servers, SAN, fault tolerance); Maintaining relationships with users:</description></item><item><title>Saint Pierre High School - Tarbes</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/education/lycee-pro-saint-pierre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/education/lycee-pro-saint-pierre/</guid><description>Obtained the Baccalaureate in Electronic and Digital Systems (BAC SEN).</description></item><item><title>IT Technician - Ormeau Polyclinic - ELSAN</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/it-technician-ormeau-polyclinic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/it-technician-ormeau-polyclinic/</guid><description/></item><item><title>IT Technician - University Hospital of Toulouse</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/it-technician-university-hospital-of-toulouse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/it-technician-university-hospital-of-toulouse/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Paul Mathou High School - Gourdan Polignan</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/education/lycee-pro-paul-mathou/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/education/lycee-pro-paul-mathou/</guid><description>Obtaining of the vocational diploma of Electrotechnics Energy Communicating Equipment (BEP ELEEC).</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/contact/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Legal notices</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/legal-notices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/legal-notices/</guid><description>The theoricher.pro website is published by the association KOMOGOTO registered at the Haute-Savoie prefecture under the number W313031584 and having its offices at : 78 allée Primavera Centre Ubidoca 19993 Pringy 74370 Annecy FRANCE.
Director of the publication: Mr Théo RICHER - pro@pulsemail.org
The Internet site https://theoricher.pro (the Site) is the exclusive property of Théo RICHER.
Hosting The website is hosted by Amazon Web Services Inc, PO Box 81226, Seattle, WA 981808-1226 - USA</description></item><item><title>Privacy policy</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/privacy-policy/</guid><description>Effective date: 24 November 2022
This page explains our policy on the collection, use and disclosure of personal data when you use the site and the choices you can make with respect to that data.
Data collected When you use my site, I may ask you to provide me with certain personally identifiable information (via the contact form) which I may use to contact you or to identify you. Personal data may include, but is not limited to :</description></item></channel></rss>