<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Experiences on Théo RICHER | Curriculum vitæ</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/</link><description>Recent content in Experiences on Théo RICHER | Curriculum vitæ</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>{currentYear} - Théo RICHER | &lt;a href="https://theoricher.pro/fr/">French Version&lt;/a> - &lt;a href="https://theoricher.pro/en/legal-notices/">Legal Notices&lt;/a> - &lt;a href="https://theoricher.pro/en/privacy-policy/">Privacy Policy&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Systems, Networks and Security Engineer - ValSoftware</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/systems-networks-engineer-valsoftware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/systems-networks-engineer-valsoftware/</guid><description>Systems, networks and security engineer in the technical department in the infrastructure service. Responsible for MCO and activity planning, supplier and service provider relations, partner prospecting. Management of several projects: migration of VMWare cluster between datacenters using the Zerto solution. Implementation of an asset management policy and solution using tools such as WAPT and GLPI.
Main tasks :
Responsible for ensuring the consistency and sustainability of the information system (servers, databases, networks, backups); Contribute to the evolution of the company&amp;rsquo;s tools, methods and internal processes; Ensuring compliance of IT infrastructures according to ANSSI best practices; Assistance to customers (N3 support); Example projects :</description></item><item><title>Project Manager: Systems, Networks and Security - ValSoftware</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/project-manager-valsoftware/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/project-manager-valsoftware/</guid><description>Apprentice in the technical department in the infrastructure service, in charge of the MCO of the internal and customers information system. Project manager on different missions: backups, monitoring, budgets, audit.
Main tasks :
Upgrading and maintaining servers in operational condition; Contribute to the evolution of tools and processes; Management of the department ; Project management and initiative taking; Example projects :
Implementation of a monitoring and visualisation solution; Management of an audit on the global overhaul of the backup system; Management of the workstation replacement campaign; Examples of activities :</description></item><item><title>System, Network and Database Administrator - ValSoftware</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/system-network-administrator-valsoftware/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/system-network-administrator-valsoftware/</guid><description>Apprentice in the technical department in the infrastructure service, in charge of the MCO of the internal and customer information system.
Main tasks :
Ensure the consistency and sustainability of the information system (servers, databases, networks, backups, workstations); Assistance to customers: N2 &amp;amp; N3 support; Update operating process; Example projects :
Implementation of a backup solution with centralized management for all Microsoft Windows servers; Implementation and management of a WDS &amp;amp; MDT deployment server; Examples of activities :</description></item><item><title>Systems, Networks and Security Technician at Spie for Airbus - SPIE ICS</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/systems-networks-security-technician-spie-airbus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/systems-networks-security-technician-spie-airbus/</guid><description>Apprentice systems and networks technician at Spie ICS for Airbus Commercial Aircraft. My role consisted of working directly with users on the customer site to provide them with technical assistance.
Main tasks :
Technical assistance (hardware and software) to users (L2); Remote or on-site intervention; Respect of intervention deadlines (SLA); Example projects :
Creation of an ISO (Live-CD) in accordance with the needs of the company and the technical constraints of the security of the Airbus information system, allowing most of the troubleshooting actions to be carried out on the user stations; Realization of a tool (based on batch) allowing to automate and accelerate some redundant administration actions; Examples of activities :</description></item><item><title>IT Technician - Ormeau Polyclinic - ELSAN</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/it-technician-ormeau-polyclinic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/it-technician-ormeau-polyclinic/</guid><description/></item><item><title>IT Technician - University Hospital of Toulouse</title><link>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/it-technician-university-hospital-of-toulouse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoricher.pro/en/experiences/it-technician-university-hospital-of-toulouse/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>